Recall that we prefer to control for risk within the Alpha factors,
我们一般都在 Alpha 因子中控制风险
rather than waiting for their risk model optimizer to do it completely for us.
而不是完全等待风险模型优化器来控制风险
This is why we make the Alpha vector dollar neutral and often also sector neutral.
所以我们让 Alpha 向量保持美元中性和行业中性
The reason we wish to control for risk early on within
之所以要提前在 Alpha 向量本身中控制风险
the Alpha vector itself is so that after the optimization,
是因为在优化之后
the portfolio weights are not too different from the original Alpha vector.
投资组合权重与原始 Alpha 向量的权重差别不大
It's natural for you to wonder why is it an issue
你自然会疑问
at the portfolio weights are nothing like the original Alpha vector?
为何投资组合权重与原始 Alpha 向量的权重差别很大是个问题？
To understand this, remember that we're evaluating
解释下 我们在评估每个 Alpha 因子时
each Alpha factor in isolation of other Alpha vectors.
将 Alpha 因子与其他 Alpha 向量孤立开来了
We evaluate the Alpha factor to see if it may be
我们评估 Alpha 向量
a good candidate to help improve the performance of a portfolio.
看看它能否有助于提高投资组合的业绩
If after optimization, the risk model significantly changes
如果在优化之后
the weights for stock so that they no
风险模型显著改变了股票的权重
longer follow the weights chosen by the Alpha vector,
不再遵守 Alpha 向量选择的权重
then we can't expect the performance of the Alpha to carry over into the portfolio.
那么我们不能期望 Alpha 带来的业绩体现到投资组合中
As the example, imagine if an Alpha vector gives most positive weight to stock ABC.
例如 假设 Alpha 向量对 ABC 分配了最高的正权重
But after the risk model neutralizes various common risks,
但是在风险模型中性化各种公共风险之后
the final portfolio weights end up shorting stock ABC,
最终的投资组合权重做空股票 ABC
then the signal from the Alpha vector which essentially says,
那么 Alpha 向量的信号“买入股票 ABC”
"Buy stock ABC" is no longer being followed.
不再被遵守
This means that the performance that we originally
这表明我们一开始希望通过
hoped to gain from using this Alpha vector
Alpha 向量获得的业绩
may not carry over or transfer to the portfolio itself.
可能没有转移到投资组合本身上
Remember that the Alpha vector is an expression of expected returns.
Alpha 向量表示预期收益率
If the portfolio weights after every optimization
如果在优化之后 投资组合权重
are very different from the original Alpha factors,
与原始 Alpha 向量的权重截然不同
then the portfolio itself may not be
那么投资组合本身可能没有体现
capturing the information expressed by those Alpha vectors.
这些 Alpha 向量表达的信息
To see how closely the optimized portfolio weights still match the original Alpha vector,
为了查看优化投资组合权重与原始 Alpha 向量权重的接近程度
we can calculate something called the transfer coefficient.
我们可以计算转移系数
The transfer coefficient measures how closely
转移系数可以衡量
the optimized portfolio weights match the original Alpha vector.
优化投资组合权重与原始 Alpha 向量权重之间的匹配程度
To get the transfer coefficient,
为了计算转移系数
we need to use portfolio optimization that includes a risk factor model.
我们需要获得包含风险因子模型的投资组合优化器
We will learn about the portfolio optimization step in a later lesson.
我们将在后面的课程中学习投资组合优化
For now, let's just assume that we have
暂时假设我们已经有一个
a portfolio optimizer that outputs portfolio weights.
输出投资组合权重的优化器
We start with our Alpha vector,
我们将 Alpha 向量
pass it through the portfolio optimization and get portfolio weights.
传入投资组合优化器中并获得投资组合权重
The transfer coefficient is the correlation
转移系数是指
between the Alpha vector and the resulting portfolio weights.
Alpha 向量与生成的投资组合权重之间的相关系数
A high transfer coefficient is a good sign that
很高的转移系数是好事
the Alpha vector has survived the portfolio optimizers risk neutralization.
表明 Alpha 向量在投资组合优化器风险中性化后还有用
The transfer coefficient is also a useful measure for
转移系数还可以衡量
another desired attribute of an Alpha factor independence from risk factors.
Alpha 因子的另一个属性 即风险因子独立性
Ideally, we would like to find
理想情况下 我们希望找到
Alpha factors that are independent of the common risk factors.
独立于公共风险因子的 Alpha 因子
If Alpha factors were too correlated with the risk factors,
如果 Alpha 因子与风险因子的关系很大
then they would also be neutralized by the risk model.
那么 Alpha 因子也应该由风险模型中性化了